

340, Mokdongseo-ro, Yangcheon-gu, Seoul, 08089, Republic of Korea

□ (+82) 10-9686-8177 | ■ tyoung96@naver.com | ★ taeyoung96.github.io | □ Taeyoung96

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

# Summary.

This is Taeyoung Kim, who wants to become an autonomous driving or robotics SW engineer. My research interests are Computer Vision and SLAM. I like to take on challenging tasks and I like to grow up with my colleagues around me. That's why I record and share what I did on my Github or Technical Blog. I would like to participate in changing the world with advanced science and technology.

#### Research Interests

**Computer Vision** Object Detection, Segmentation, Depth Estimation

**SLAM** Visual SLAM, Visual Odometry

#### Education

**Kwang Woon University** Seoul, S.Korea

**B.S. IN SCHOOL OF ROBOTICS** 

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022 (Expected)

- Current GPA: 4.07 / 4.50, Current Major GPA: 4.50 / 4.50
- Club: BARAM (Robotics Academic Group) [2020 Staff], DAISY (English Conversation Club) [2019 Spring President]

# Work Experience \_

#### Computer Vision Lab @Korea Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

UNDERGRADUATE LAB INTERN (ADVISOR: PROF. SANGPIL KIM) · Research on computer vision using an Event camera Mar. 2021 - Present

#### KIST(Korea Institute of Science and Technology)

Seoul, S.Korea

STUDENT INTERN (ADVISOR: DR. KANGGEON KIM)

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Research on Monocular Depth Estimation
- Participated in KIST disinfect robot (AI Disinfection Robot) project [Video]

## Image Process System Lab @Kwang Woon Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor: Prof. Donggyu Sim)

Mar. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- · Research on Image Processing based on Deep learning
- · Participated in seminars related to Deep Learning and Image Processing

## **Publication**

#### INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE

UR2021, Taeyoung Kim, Omer Faruk Ince, JongBeom Baek, Jun-Sik Kim, KangGeon Kim, 2021.3

**IEEE** 

"Denser Monocular SLAM applied Depth Estimation"

#### DOMESTIC CONFERENCE

KSPC2020, Naseong Kwon, Taeyoung Kim, Subin Kim, Joohyung Byeon, Jongsuk Lee, Donggyu Sim, 2020.9 "Luma Mapping with Chroma Scaling based on CNN feature map for VVC subjective quality improvement"

## **Honors & Awards**

#### **AWARDS**

2020.11 Dean's List, for Academic Excellence

KwangWoon Univ. NAVER CLOUD

2020.9 **5th Place on B-track**, Korea Health Datathon 2020

KwangWoon Univ.

**PLATFORM** 

2019.10 Dean's List, for Academic Excellence

#### HONORS

National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship, 2020

for the students with excellent grades, those who have been recommended by the university

2019-2 Full tuition Scholarship, for Top seat last semester

Korea Student Aid Foundation KwangWoon Univ.

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

# Skills

**Programming** C++/C, Python, JAVA, Matlab Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras Framework

DevOps Git, Docker, ROS Languages Korean, English

# **Extracurricular Activity**

**Technical Blogs** Github blog

WRITERS May. 2020 - Present

- · Writing some posts about lecture summary, paper review, some tips for developments.
- To share what I have studied with others and to remember it longer.

#### **Monocular Depth Estimation with ORB-SLAM2**

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT Sep. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- I was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model.
- I used 'Monocular Depth Estimation with Transfer Learning pretrained MobileNetV2' model and applied to ORB-SLAM2 also compared with ORB-SLAM2(Monocular mode), ORB-SLAM2(RGB-D mode)
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

**KCCV 2020** Korea computer vision society

PARTICIPANT Aug. 2020

• Participated to know about the trend of Computer Vision

#### Using deep learning for data analysis and image processing (Basic)

Korea open source software

STUDENTS

• Studied lectures which is related to the using Deep learning framework(Keras)

# **Runner Alarm System based on Deep Learning**

Apr. 2020 - Jun. 2020 PERSONAL TOY PROJECT

- · I wanted to distinguish between walking children and running children with an object detection model.
- When children are running for an amount of time, a beep sounds.
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

TAEYOUNG KIM · CURRICULUM VITAE FEBRUARY 27, 2021